what's up everybody this is Nick at
bobbed.com today we are talking about
the best nitric oxide supplements for
you we're not talking about nuts for the
car we're talking about no to make your
gains explode sounds a bit over the top
but what's interesting about nitric
oxide is that if you are not aware the
point of it is that it is increasing
vasodilation so it makes your blood
vessels a bit wider so more blood can
flow through them now there are a couple
of effects to that number one yeah you
get more veiny during a workout it's a
nice aesthetic thing a lot of people
like that but in addition to that extra
blood flow can indeed help to have extra
ergogenic effects it can help you to
have a more productive workout there's
also significant evidence that getting
more blood to the muscle can indeed
increase hypertrophy after the workout
meaning actual bigger muscles but it's
also quite healthful as well so there
are plenty of interviews to take Nitric
Oxide but most people is for better
pumps and better gains in the gym and in
this video today we're going to be
talking about all the best supplements
from the best nitric oxide supplements
overall so that's beetroot supplements
which is a good natural source of the
stuff and more so stick around you're
not going to miss this one now before I
go on I'm going to make it clear this is
not medical advice and I am not a doctor
this kind of stuff is especially
important to note when you're talking
about blood pressure and blood vessel
dilation so if you're planning to make
any changes to your supplement regimen
or your nutrition regimen or your
workout regimen make absolutely
certainly speak to a medical
professional before moving forward
[Music]
boom
now before I tell you a little bit more
about what nitric oxide is I am going to
tell you right now because actually here
for what the best supplement is on our
list it's this one right here from huge
supplements this one is called magnify
it's got a very fancy scorpion on the
bottle what we like about magnify is
that it is nice and portable it's easy
to put some pills in your bag or in your
pocket before you go to the gym before
you go to work before you go to the gym
there's also a lot of really interesting
well-dosed ingredients in here and if
you're familiar with this area of
supplementation you'll already know
words like citrulline and Arginine and
norvalene but also there are some other
interesting ingredients here
specifically vas or six which is a very
curious green tea extract which can
potentially help to increase the
bioavailability of these other
ingredients specifically in the realm of
nitric oxide production basically mean
that your cardiovascular system is
working smarter not harder there's like
less strain on the heart than can
potentially happen with a whole lot of
other nitric oxide producing ingredients
but what is nitric oxide what are we
talking about here well nitric oxide is
an essential molecule that signals 12
blood vessels to expand it's important
to know that we're not actually
consuming nitric oxide in any of these
supplements rather we're consuming
ingredients and compounds that have
significant links to increasing nitric
oxide in the body so the most famous
natural example of this is indeed
beetroot powder beetroot juice there's
been a lot of studies on these that have
shown that taking beetroot juice
supplements and also other ingredients
that are linked to nitric oxide
Productions can yes help to increase
vasodilation help with blood flow and
there have also been studies on
ergogenic benefits in the gym and we've
seen specific results in cyclists and
aerobic output and also some strength
training outputs as well across the
board having more blood flow can
unsurprisingly lead to better results so
that's why I love you like Technic oxide
supplements but to be clear it's a
little like creatine in that creatine
has a lot of really solid ergogenic
benefits like power output but a lot of
people take them for the aesthetic
benefits of slightly larger muscles
nitric oxide there are lots of ergogenic
benefits to it but also we can't deny
that a lot of people like them because
it gets you big Palms your muscles
getting bigger at the gym and you get
some nice vascularity as well so again
huge supplements magnified took our pick
for the best supplement overall here
these ingredients include a 1500
milligrams of arginine which contains
several different types of arginine as
well you've also get a thousand
milligrams of beetroot extract which as
we mentioned is like the most potent
natural form of a nitric oxide
increasing ingredients then you've also
got a little bit of a citrulline there's
some noveline there's green coffee bean
extract and there's also black pepper
extract which is actually really
important in supplements like this
because a lot of research has shown that
black pepper extract can help to absorb
the ingredients you're consuming you
haven't seen a lot of prescription
medications but also in supplements as
well because like the data is pretty
convincing across the board the dosage
here is six capsules which might sound
like a lot you take it about 20 to 30
minutes per workout what we like about
it is that it allows you to easily
adjust the amount that you take before
each gym session so if you decide that
you actually feel the effects on less or
on more that's easy enough to do without
futzing around with powder and scoops
and Shaker bottles because they are
capsules it wasn't no brain it's the
name this also the best nitric oxide
pills that you can buy on the market
it's worth noting that although it is
this very snazzy purple color they are
made from gelatin which means it's made
from animals like probably bones so that
means it's not really great for
vegetarians or vegans probably not be
trying to keep Halal or kosher as well
but if none of those issues for you this
is definitely worth recommending in
addition keeping them from gelatin as
opposed to vegetarian capsules may make
them a bit more shelf stable at higher
temperatures and perhaps most
importantly it does keep the cost down
as well so we don't normally penalize
around too much for gelatin capsules
a runner-up for the best nitric oxide
supplement is transparent labs this
company is a really legit reputation and
it's well deserved for being very
transparent with their ingredients if
you go to the website they'll give you
like the precise dosages of every single
ingredient and studies as to why they
included it which is a level of
transparency that is sadly not super
super common in the industry transparent
Labs is really good here the most
interesting aspect of the ingredients
here is they include a combination of
ingredients called no3t that's a mixture
of Agony nitrate and beta e nitrate and
there's some evidence that suggests that
combining those two can make it a bit
more stable and also make it have a
longer lasting effect during a workout
there's some interesting research there
that a lot of folks find really
promising in and or supplements there's
another interesting ingredient here and
often see called glutathione you're
getting 250 milligrams of that and
there's evidence that it might help to
reduce oxidative stress which is a big
one when you're working out while also
helping to encourage healthy blood flow
too pine bark extract and vitamin C are
also in here to run out the antioxidant
effect and the vitamin C also along with
the estrogen which is a combination of
astragalus root and notoginseng root
similar a little bit to black pepper
extract in that vitamin C and also the
acid gin can help to absorb everything
in there as well so it's really nice
when we see supplement companies adding
in ingredient for absorption especially
multiple ingredients for absorption here
while also the vitamin C having an
antioxidant effect as well which could
potentially help to improve recovery we
also named transparent Labs supplement
the best for Pump and vascularity in the
realm of oxide supplements again because
that no3t so that Arginine and beta e
nitrate should have implications for yes
your pump and vascularity lasting for
longer which is like a nice aesthetic
benefit but also should have
implications through performance in the
gym and also hypertrophy after the gym
as well plus the other ingredients here
that uh that are linked to blood flow
like the glutathione has links to less
oxidative stress and also again to
healthier blood flow so what we really
like about this overall is that the
ingredients here are linked to increased
nitric oxide production but also for a
longer time and also there's plenty of
Entry ingredients that's help to reduce
oxidative stress as well overall helping
to reduce the stress you're getting on
the body and especially when you're
having ergogenic AIDS when you're
working out you're working out harder
and longer there is an argument to be
made that you need to pay extra
attention to antioxidants reducing
oxidative stress and your recovery as
well so this is a really nice
well-rounded approach to a nitric oxide
supplementation plus the capsules here
are vegetarian so if you are a
vegetarian or you just want to limit
your consumptive animal products this is
going to be good to go you do have to
get 4k at a time but it is less than a
number one pick and again it makes it a
little bit easier to judge how much you
want to take for each workout now before
I go any further we do have a written
version of this video if you want to
check that out I know I'm throwing a lot
of information here at you so if you
want to take this in at your own pace or
if you want to check out some of the
studies and research I've been talking
about and just make sure I'm not full of
BS you can just Google bar Bend best
nitric oxide supplements the whole
article is going to come up and you can
take a look verify and make your own
decisions as to which of these
supplements is right for you
next up a question we get asked a lot is
the best nitric oxide supplement for
citrulline and for that we're definitely
going with huge supplements pump serum
citrulline if you're not aware is a
non-essential amino acid it's not really
involved in muscle production rather it
has a role in helping the body rid
itself of harmful toxins siciline is
commonly found in watermelon citrulline
comes from the it's like the Latin or
the Greek word for watermelon and it has
a very well-known role in helping to
promote vasodilation as well so they've
done really interesting research on
cyclists and Tennis plays and a few
other types of athletes showing like
increases in power production and also
some endurance as well so a lot of folks
really like essentially the trouble with
citrulline is that you kind of need a
fairly large dose of it to have an
effective dose there are plenty of
supplements out there that'll give you
one gram and say look see we have
citrulline but the research suggests you
need at least five grams of it this one
here is eight grams of citrulline per
servings but a lot of other interesting
ingredients in here as well like you've
got a solid three grams of beta eat
anhydrous that's a really nice it
actually exceeds the minimum effective
dose you typically see in studies just
like two and a half grams throughout a
day get a nice three grams of beta in
which can also play a role invested
dilation and there's been extra studies
on this one with regard to the power
output like they've done studies on
folks in the back squat and the bench
press and seeing significant
improvements there and you also got
stuff like glycer pump which could help
to Aid with hydration and also nutrient
absorption along with the black pepper
extract which can also help nutrient
absorption so we really do like it when
our supplements pay extra attention to
helping you to absorb the stuff you're
consuming this is a whole Suite of
ingredients that are really interesting
for blood flow but the eight grams of
citrulline is what we're really
highlighting here because that's what
people are asking us about so definitely
pump Serum is a good one there it is not
really it's technically a pre-workout
but there's no caffeine in it so it's
non-stem and you can pretty much have it
anytime
[Music]
huge supplements made a second
appearance on this list and that's the
best pre-workout for nitric oxide so
this is a non-stem powder from a huge
supplements with plenty of ingredients
nitric oxide this is a stem one so as a
free workout you're getting a pretty
significant 350 milligrams of caffeine
in here that is about twice actually a
bit over twice we'd get in an average
like 12 ounce cold brew from your local
coffee place it's very high in caffeine
to be fair 100 milligrams of the
caffeine is slow release so it shouldn't
have quite as big an immediate hit and
then steep drop off there's some giant
amounts of caffeine nonetheless it is a
very strong dose of caffeine here but in
addition to the caffeine there are a lot
of ingredients here that are the same
and have the same dosages as you're
going to get in pump serum so you've got
that same eight grams of citrulline here
you've also got that same three grams of
beta en anhydrous as well as a lot of
other interesting ingredients in
pre-workouts that could potentially help
to improve blood flow and help with
endurance like beta alanine as well as
in here you're getting three and a half
grams of that again mostly workouts like
I'm comfortable saying it'll be
effective at 1.6 grams of beta alanine
that's generally considered the minimum
here again three and a half grams the
good news about all these really high
dosages is that if the caffeine is too
much for you you can have less like you
can have like a good half of one scoop
and you're still getting pretty effect
effective doses of all these ingredients
as well so that's something I really
like about wrecked it might seem really
strong but you can titrate it to your
own Comfort there but anyway a lot of
caffeine in this and a lot of
ingredients to help with nitric oxide
production and it's got that black
pepper extract as well so that's
definitely our favorite pre-workout for
nitric oxide production
[Music]
rounding out the list here we've got on
its for the best natural nitric oxide
supplement if you're familiar with the
brand or the supplement industry at
large that probably shouldn't be much of
a surprise because on it they had this
really holistic kind of approach to the
supplementation and then a lot of the
ingredients you're going to find a real
emphasis on natural components so
they're really like using like fruit
extracts and like stinging metal
extracts and things like that in a
variety of supplements so in the total
nitric oxide one from on it what you're
getting here is blends of like grape
seed extract Apple extract acerola
Cherry extract it's also got careful's
mango fruit powder which is pretty
interesting it's 100 Roundup mango but
they've had some interesting Swiss does
on this including a randomized double
blind study on humans that found it to
increase a micro circulation and also to
generally improve the endothelial
function in the body which refers to the
vascular system so it's like an
interesting kind of all-natural way of
approaching increasing blood flow but we
also think this one the best nitric
oxide supplement with beets because
baits as I mentioned earlier that's
generally considered the most potent
natural way to get ingredients that are
going to help your magic oxide
production and this one contains
fermented beetroot in an interesting
proprietary blend and fermented beet
powder interestingly enough when
compared to like regular beet juice
powder has twice as many nitrates so
it's interesting way to get like a more
dense supplement like you don't have
quite as much volume to get the same
effect this is a completely all-natural
supplement no artificial flavors or
sweeteners it's got an interesting what
they call Harvest fruit flavor which is
pretty heavy on beetroots and mango
unsurprisingly there's also no caffeine
in this either so this is considered a
non-stem pre-workout if you like but
because it's non-stem you can take this
any time of the day to get those effects
you don't necessarily have to take a
pre-workout because its effects are kind
of ongoing but like acute increase and
then drop
foreign
[Music]
list of the best nitric oxide
supplements the way that we landed on
this list there were like a few areas we
looked at
um naturally we looked at the research
and how robust the research is
especially in the area of beet powder
and citrally which tend to get the most
attention so we look at the dosages of
that we also had a good look at uh the
differences between L-Arginine and
citrulline which have like very similar
sort of research and effects ascribed to
them citrulline though is generally
considered to be a bit more effective at
getting done what agamine is intended to
do so we like to lean a bit more on
citrulline which again is why you see
plenty of it here but nonetheless the
inclusion of arginine is not a
detracting factor in these settlements
in our opinion on top of that there are
a few forms of sichling out there like
there's l-citrulline l-citrulline malate
which tends to like taste a little bit
better because it's bound with malic
acid which is famously found in apples
and gives it one of those like nice sort
of like taut sweet tastes uh besides
that though there doesn't seem to be any
difference with regard to the
effectiveness and also of course the
dosage as well like we had a look at the
dosage in the ingredients list relative
to what the research suggests is going
to be effective so there's things to
keep in mind when you're talking about
purchasing a nitric oxide supplement
it's also about taking a look at whether
or not you want to get powders or pills
as well each have their pros and cons
personally again I just really like the
portability of pills and not having to
worry about not only having a water
source but also a bottle in which to
shake it so I like to take the pills
yeah obviously there's plenty of
benefits for your powder as well namely
you can have a delicious drink as well
lastly do make sure you speak to Medical
Professional before you get started on
these we say that if we're just talking
about protein powder but you're talking
about this kind of stuff that a lot of
people are taking to help with their
blood flow and they get it in their head
so this is going to make a good
substitution for medications and that
kind of stuff we're not saying that at
all if you have real concerns about like
your circulatory system your endothelial
function that kind of stuff or just
anything any reason at all make sure you
speak your doctor before starting any
new supplement regimen like that all
right and that does it for our list of
the best antioxide supplements again if
you want to read the full written
version of this article check out some
of the studies have a look at the
ingredients in a bit more depth just
Google bar Ben best nitric oxide
supplements and it should pop right up
so thanks for watching I hope you
learned something and I will see in the
next one
[Music]